<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Antony Mapfumo</title>
    <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/categories/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Antony Mapfumo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 13:42:58 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mapfumo.github.io/categories/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solana Vault Program - Part 1 - Backend</title>
      <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/solana-vault-program-part-1-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 13:42:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/solana-vault-program-part-1-backend/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to this beginner-friendly guide to Solana programs — the engine behind some of the fastest and most cost-efficient decentralized applications in the blockchain ecosystem.
Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to Solana or transitioning from other blockchain platforms, this tutorial is designed to help you start building quickly and confidently. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn what makes Solana programs unique, how they take advantage of the network&amp;rsquo;s high-performance architecture, and why more developers are choosing Solana for their next-generation applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Escape Rust: Rust for Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/you-cant-escape-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 07:29:49 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/you-cant-escape-rust/</guid>
      <description>I thought I could “get away with it” — avoiding Rust, that is. A few years back, I started learning Rust, but honestly, it was for all the wrong reasons. I thought it would be just &amp;ldquo;cool to know&amp;rdquo; this relatively young language. As it turns out, that’s not exactly the best motivator when dealing with a language known for a steep learning curve and a strict compiler. Fast forward to 2024, and my career path has taken me deeper into blockchain development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
