<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Antony Mapfumo</title>
    <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/categories/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Antony Mapfumo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 18:00:58 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mapfumo.github.io/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Specialisation - A Brief Course Review</title>
      <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/deep_learning_specialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 18:00:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/deep_learning_specialisation/</guid>
      <description>I have just completed Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialisation course by deeplearning.ai available through Coursera. This is my summary and opinion of the course offering. The specialisation consists of 5 courses and it is suggested that they be completed in 3 months by devoting 11 hours per week. It really depends on your previous knowledge, experience and how quickly you can grasp the concepts. When stuck with the assignments and concepts I found the forum to be very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iec 61850</title>
      <link>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/iec-61850/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:30:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mapfumo.github.io/posts/iec-61850/</guid>
      <description>The IEC 61850 is at the heart of data communications in the smart grid. The IEC (International Electrotechnical Commission) 61850 standard outlines a framework for communication between several single devices in the power system. The standard was designed to separate the data model from method of communication, address the importance of a structured approach to the design of substation automation systems, utilise existing technologies like Ethernet and TCP/IP, simplify system configuration, device measurement sharing and to enable vendor independence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
