<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Antony Mapfumo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Antony Mapfumo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 18:00:58 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Specialisation - A Brief Course Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/deep_learning_specialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 18:00:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/deep_learning_specialisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just completed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/instructor/andrewng&#34;&gt;Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning&#34;&gt;Deep Learning Specialisation&lt;/a&gt; course by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deeplearning.ai/&#34;&gt;deeplearning.ai&lt;/a&gt; available through &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2WjYrPB&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;. This is my summary and opinion of the course offering. The specialisation consists of 5 courses and it is suggested that they be completed in 3 months by devoting 11 hours per week. It really depends on your previous knowledge, experience and how quickly you can grasp the concepts. When stuck with the assignments and concepts I found the forum to be very helpful. I found the assignments to reasonably difficult. The only thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t like is that by forcing you to complete the given code (complete missing blanks) you are a bit constrained. For example it would be nice to state the function signature and leave it to the student to implement it in their own way. The good thing is that one can always make such suggestions through the forums. The courses don&amp;rsquo;t have to be completed in any particular order but I found it more helpful to follow the suggested order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
